https://www.erchonia.com/gdpr-privacy-policy/

GDPR Privacy Policy
Erchonia Corporation
Erchonia Corporation is committed to protecting the information you share with us. As a Medical Device Manufacturer, we will collect and share certain information about you as part of providing our services. We may collect your details as a clinic, distributor, consumer, supplier, or website user.
If you are an EU citizen:
Erchonia Corporation (located in the United States of America) is the parent company of Erchonia Lasers Limited. Erchonia Lasers Limited is a company registered in England & Wales (no. 08681472). Erchonia Lasers Limited’s registered address is; Howbery Business Park Benson Lane, Wallingford, Oxford, OX10 8BA.
Erchonia Lasers Limited is registered with the Information Commissioners Office (ICO) under registration number ZA388336. Erchonia Lasers Limited is classified as a data controller.
This Privacy Policy is effective from 01st May 2018 and complies with the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) that comes into force across the EU on 25th May 2018.
Key Definition Personal Data:
Any data that could be used to identify you as an individual. For example, a work email address, social media name, phone number, etc. GDPR updates data protection to reflect the changes in technology.
1. What do we collect about you?
As a Clinic/Distributor, the information we collect may include the following:
Name
Job Title
Address
Email and phone contact details
Records of interactions including meetings, emails and calls
History of Purchases/Usage of services
Information from third parties regarding insurance, credit reference, fraud, debt
As a Supplier, the information we collect may include the following:
Name
Job Title
Address
Email and phone contact details
Records of interactions including meetings, emails and calls
History of Purchases/Usage of Services
Information from third parties regarding insurance, credit reference, fraud, debt
2. How will we use this information about you?
As a Clinic/Distributor, we will use your information for the following purposes:
Provide you with our products/services
Collecting your data
Processing and storing your data
Communicating with you
Managing any aspect of providing the service including customer service
Maintaining a record of the services we have provided to you
Carrying out credit reference and fraud checks
To comply with legal and regulatory obligations, requirements and guidance
For the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims
Sharing your details with third-parties to fulfil accounting and invoicing
Improve our services, internal performance, training and standards
As a Supplier, we will use your information for the following purposes:
Purchasing your products/services
Collecting your data
Processing and storing your data
Communicating with you
Managing any aspect of purchasing your products/services
Maintaining a record of the products/services you have provided to us
Carrying out credit reference and fraud checks
To comply with legal and regulatory obligations, requirements and guidance
For the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims
Sharing your details with third-parties to fulfil accounting and invoicing
Improve our services, internal performance, training and standards
3. How do we collect information about you?
As a Clinic/Distributor we may collect your information from the following sources, amongst others:
You directly
Your colleagues
Via our employees’ business development activities
Social media including LinkedIn
Distributors or Clinics
Suppliers
Third parties such as credit reference agencies
Industry events & publications
As a Supplier we may collect your information from the following sources, amongst others:
You directly
Your colleagues
Via your employees’ business development activities
Social media including LinkedIn
Distributors or Clinics
Suppliers
Third parties such as credit reference agencies
Industry events & publications
4. Why we process the information including our legal basis?
We process your data to complete our activities as a Medical Device Manufacturer. The below explains the lawful basis we use to process your data.
As a Clinic/Distributor:
We believe it is in our legitimate interest to collect and process your data where we believe you would be interested in our products/services. For example; if you are a Distributor of medical devices or if you are Clinic providing consumers with cosmetic procedures.
At times we will request your explicit consent to process and store your data. Where this is required we will inform you at the time and provide you with clear information about what you are consenting to. For example; you subscribing to our newsletter about industry news & products or completing an enquiry from at an exhibition.
Where we establish a contractual relationship with you and/or your employer we will collect and process your data to enable us to meet these contractual agreements.
Where we are required by regulatory and statutory obligations we will retain your data to meet these legal For example; tax, fraud/crime, data protection.
As a Supplier:
We believe it is in our legitimate interest to collect and process your data where we may be interested in purchasing your service. For example; if you are a provider of delivery services, office supplies, accountancy software, etc.
At times we will request your explicit consent to process and store your data. Where this is required we will inform you at the time and provide you with clear information about what you are consenting to. For example; you subscribing to our newsletter about industry news & products.
Where we establish a contractual relationship with you and/or your employer we will collect and process your data to enable us to meet these contractual agreements.
Where we are required by regulatory and statutory obligations we will retain your data to meet these legal For example; tax, fraud/crime, data protection.
5. Who we share your personal data with?
We share your information with selected third-parties. These include, but are not limited to:
Clinics;
Distributors;
Suppliers;
IT Support;
Legal and Professional Advisers;
Marketing Advisors;
Conference Venues;
Navision – An accounting system;
Salesforce – A CRM system we use to securely manage our data;
Office365 – An email and productivity system;
LiveDrive – file storage software;
Any regulatory authority or statutory body pursuant to a request for information or any legal obligation which applies to us.
6. Transfers outside of the EEA
As a Medical Device Manufacturer, we may need to share some information with third-parties based outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). We are committed to:
Sharing as little information as is required;
Ensuring contractual agreements are in place
Only sharing information when required to fulfil contracts.
7. Special (or Sensitive) Personal Data
Where we collect any special (or sensitive) personal information – examples include; race, ethnic origin, politics, religion, trade union membership, health, sex life, or sexual orientation – we will ask for your explicit consent. This includes any information regarding criminal convictions.
8. Marketing
If you provide your explicit consent to receive marketing, we may send you:
Information about our products and services
Our newsletter covering products & market information
You can remove your consent to marketing by contacting info@erchoniaeurope.com.
9. Cookies
We use cookies on our website to help improve your experience. A cookie is a small text file that is downloaded on to your computer when you visit a website. Cookies are used by many websites and we have listed those present on our website below. There are two types of cookie; Session – these expire when you close the website, and Persistent – these stay on your device for a set time period and we have stated the expiry times below.
Name
Provider
Purpose
Expiry
Type
wc_cart_hash_#
Erchonia
Necessary in the running of the website
Youtube.com
Unique ID registered on mobile devices to enable GPS tracking
Session
HTTP
NID
Youtube.com
Unique ID registered to identify returning visitors. ID used for targeted advertising.
Persistent – 6 months
HTTP
PREF
Youtube.com
Unique ID registered to understand how visitor uses youtube across the web
Persistent – 8 months
HTTP
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
Youtube.com
Estimate users bandwith to deliver best quality video playback
Persistent – 179 days
HTTP
YSC
Youtube.com
Unique ID for video viewed statistics
Session
HTTP
You can find out more about cookies and how to disable them using your browser by visiting https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/.
10. Other websites
This privacy policy only applies to this website. Our website includes links to other websites, on visiting the link you should check their privacy policies.
11. Changes to our privacy policy
From time to time we will update our privacy policy on this page. This version was last updated on 01st May 2018.
12. Your Rights:
You can find the contact details for our Data Protection Officer below or email info@erchoniaeurope.com.
Right to be Informed – you can request information about the categories of data we hold on you by downloading this form or contacting our Data Protection Officer.
Right to Access – you can request a copy of the data we hold on you by downloading this form or contacting our Data Protection Officer.
Right to Rectification – You can request we update/correct any information we hold.
Right to Erasure – You can request we delete the information we hold. In some cases, we have a legal right to retain your data, if this is the case we will explain why.
Right to Restrict Processing – You can request we stop processing your data but will continue to hold it.
Right to Data Portability – You can request we transfer your data to a third party or data controller of your choice.
Right to Object – You can request we stop processing your data in relation to a legitimate interest or marketing purposes.
Rights related to automated decision making including profiling – You can object to use using automated software to process your data and make decisions.
You can complain to the Information Commissioners Office by visiting https://ico.org.uk/concerns/. Registration number: ZA388336.
We will respond to any of the above within 30 calendar days.
13. How to contact us:
If you have any questions, please contact our data protection officer via info@erchoniaeurope.com or by writing to:
Data Protection Officer
Erchonia Lasers Limited
Howbery Business Park
Benson Lane
Wallingford
Oxford
OX10 8BA
Last Updated on June 18, 2018 by Erchonia
We are using cookies to give you the best experience on our website.
You can find out more about which cookies we are using or switch them off in settings.
GDPR Privacy Policy
Accept
Change cookie settings
Privacy Overview
Powered by GDPR plugin
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful.
You can adjust all of your cookie settings by navigating the tabs on the left hand side.
Enable All
Save Changes
